I hereby decree that
Prime Minister Cao Cao,
...lead the Imperial Army,
...to pacify the rebels Liu Bei
and Sun Quan.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
These people are loyal to the Han Empire.
They followed us to
escape Cao Cao's regime.
If we do not protect civilians,
...then what is the meaning of this war?
An alliance will strengthen us both.
When a loser joins forces with a coward,
...what can they accomplish?
What the Southlands need is unity!
My decision to fight is final.
Anyone who dares mention surrender...
...will end up like this table!
You need to fight this war.
I am not afraid of him.
I have been waiting for this day!
We shall fight, not waste time with words.
Make camp there!
On the bank facing Red Cliff.
Tomorrow we may be enemies.
If that day ever comes,
...it will be each man for himself
Cao Cao has no experience in naval warfare.
He must rely on Admirals
Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
If I can eliminate them,
...his navy will be powerless
Nice play!
Goal!
These little monkeys are getting quicker!
The Prime Minister's order
to practice Cuju...
...has toughened these kids up.
Follow closely.
Carry him inside quickly.
Follow me.
Just my stomach growling.
Yes!
Goal!
What do you think? Not bad, right?
Block him!
Yeah!
That pot isn't wide enough.
You would miss no matter how wide it was.
Pitch pot is a game for aristocrats...
...not for soldiers in wartime.
Your Honor,
how'd you throw that bull's eye?
Concentration.
When the enemy is over-confident,
...we must double our concentration.
With concentration,
you can kill a giant with a pebble.
Your Highness, Zhou Yu's army is small.
He'll have to resort to guerilla warfare.
That last puny victory...
...has made Zhou Yu cocky.
He's no guerilla warrior.
He will confront us face to face.
They are readying for battle.
We need a strategy to counter them.
Cao Cao wants to surround us...
...without breaking the
basic rules of strategy.
The first army to the field will be rested.
The second army will arrive exhausted.
Attack where the enemy is least prepared.
Strike where they least expect it.
We must concentrate all forces...
...on their strongest position.
Naval victory depends on...
...Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
We are loyal to Your Highness until death.
Cao Cao underestimates us.
He will never expect us to hit their navy.
What is your name?
Private Sun Shucai.
You are an outstanding player...
...and a good soldier.
From this day forward...
...you are promoted to battalion commander.
Thank you, Your Highness!
Everyone must practice hard at Cuju.
Only with tough bodies can we win this war.
Once the Southlands are subdued,
...your families will be exempt
from taxes for three years.
Thank you, Your Highness!
What are you doing?
I'm... setting these birds free.
That's very kind of you.
You're leaving?
By your accent, I bet you're a Southerner.
That's right.
Southerners are warm-hearted people.
Northerners are free-spirited.
I'm kind of dumb.
People say my entire life...
You're not dumb, just too honest.
You're good at Cuju.
Thanks for heading the ball.
What's your name?
My name is...
Look at the size of me...
My mother calls me Piggy.
Piggy?
So you can play Cuju right?
You kidding? I only know hacky-sack.
Congratulations on your promotion.
So does a commander get bigger meals?
You're a big officer now.
You can eat as much as you want.
Are you fighting just to
fill your stomach?
Mother says my stomach is a bottomless pit.
My family's too poor to feed me.
We're Pit and Piggy!
What a pair!
The new environment has made our men ill.
They are weak from a long war...
...and have lost all immunity.
So typhoid quickly...
Can it be cured?
Yes...
...but not overnight
How many have died?
Over a hundred.
In a few days, it will be out of control.
We must bury them right away.
No burials! We must cremate.
Cremation is the only way
to stop its spread.
- Ready the funeral pyres.
- Yes, sir
Hold on.
Epidemic outbreak.
The climate has weakened Cao Cao's army.
Disease is rampant Great.
Your Honor, let's seize
this chance and attack.
The navy is still healthy.
We must not act recklessly.
Your Honor, this is the time to attack!
Yes!
This is a battle of honor.
Even war must be fair.
Your Highness...
...isn't this a bit inhumane?
Cast off the soldiers of the dead!
What's the matter?
Pull the boats here.
Look, what is that?
Pull it here.
Pull the boats here.
- Go report this to the general.
- Yes, sir.
Pile weapons and armor here.
Put the corpses there.
Yes, sir.
Get away from here.
Don't touch them!
They died from typhoid!
Move! It's contagious!
Move! Don't touch anything!
Get out of here!
Everyone must leave!
Escort these people away!
This is for your own good.
This place is infected.
Leave here immediately.
Cao Cao is truly ruthless.
Those soldiers have touched corpses.
I've quarantined them...
...so they do not infect others
And the villagers?
I fear many have already been infected.
Cao Cao has stooped to evil tricks.
This is psychological warfare.
He's attacking our morale.
How to dispose of the bodies?
These are the bodies of our enemies.
Feed them to the fishes.
No, we must lay them to rest.
No burials.
We must cremate them.
I lift my drink and sing a song.
For who knows if life be short or long?
Man's life is but the morning dew.
Past days many, future ones few.
The melancholy my heart begets.
Comes from cares I cannot forget.
Who can unravel these woes of mine?
I know but one man... the God of Wine!
Disciples dressed in blue.
My heart worries for you.
You are the cause.
Of this song without pause.
Across the bank a deer bleats...
...in the wilds where it eats.
Honored guests I salute.
Strike the harp! Play the flute!
Bright is the moon's spark.
Never ceasing, never dark.
Thoughts of you from deep inside.
Cannot settle, cannot subside.
Stars around the moon are few.
Southward the crows flew.
Flying with no rest.
Where shall they nest?
No mountain too steep.
No ocean too deep.
Sages rush when guests call.
So at their feet...
...the empire does fall!
Take your time. Careful, it's hot.
More fall sick every day.
You have enough medicine?
Cassia trees are scarce here.
Our men will keep searching.
Can cassia cure typhoid?
It will ease current symptoms.
But a true cure requires other ingredients.
Let me take a look.
Hurry! Carry our men out!
Move it!
Stand up, let's go.
Stop! What do you think you're doing?
What are you doing?
General, what are you doing?
These patients cannot be moved.
Hurry! Put our men on the horses.
Please, these men must not leave.
They are still ill.
You're leaving?
Viceroy, this epidemic
is beyond our control.
I have barely twenty thousand men.
If this continues, I might lose everything.
I must retreat and reformulate my strategy.
You withdraw at a moment like this?
You proposed this alliance.
Now with our lives at stake, you flee?
This is betrayal.
You can't say that.
We are men of our word.
But look what has happened to our men.
So our men count for nothing?
- Selfishness.
- Who is selfish?
- Zhang Fei!
- General!
My Lord, the battle is set.
- How can you...
- Zhu-ge Liang
I have seen over a decade of defeat.
I cannot endure another setback.
Even soldiers must obey
the law of survival.
We must not lose our allies' trust.
I know you feel strongly.
But in chaotic times,
you cannot live on justice alone.
It's time I let others
fight the tough battles.
One day you will understand this.
Liu Bei.
It was an honor to fight
alongside your men.
We believed in the same goal.
Achieving it will not be so easy after all.
Take care.
We shall meet again.
Aren't you leaving?
A man must honor his promises.
If I start something, I see it to the end.
Anyone who talks like that is insane.
Then we are all insane.
Your Highness, tea is ready.
Brother, scouts report...
...the typhoid was successful.
The Southlands are in chaos.
- Good.
- One more thing.
Liu Bei has left with all his men.
Good.
Their alliance is broken.
Excellent.
Swift as the wind.
Gentle as a forest.
Fierce as fire.
Firm as a mountain.
If you hate war,
...why can you quote "The Art of War"?
To understand you,
...I must sneak glances at your books.
A thousand books cannot
equal a cup of your tea.
I'm happy so long as you enjoy it.
I wish we could invite Cao Cao for tea.
Forget the war and just enjoy the scenery.
Wouldn't that be great?
I doubt he appreciates the art of tea.
You wield your sword...
...like you know a way to beat Cao Cao
A way as mysterious as darkness.
And as powerful as thunder.
It is time for us to act.
Greetings, Your Highness.
How goes the naval training, Admirals?
Very well, Your Highness.
We're using iron beams to join the fleet.
Our men are Northerners
and new to naval battle.
Now our ships shall be
stable as solid ground.
Not even a storm will make our men seasick.
- Can they be separated?
- Of course.
Men, separate the ships.
Unlocking the iron beams
separates the ships.
The fleet will move into pincer formation...
...ready for battle.
You truly are naval experts...
...to invent this tactic.
Thank you, Your Highness.
- Jiang Gan.
- At your service, Your Highness.
You grew up with Zhou Yu, right?
Yes, we were childhood friends.
Cross the river. Urge him to surrender.
Surrender?
Zhou Yu's loyalty to Sun Quan runs deep.
I'm afraid he won't...
The Southlands are falling apart.
Liu Bei has fled.
Now is the time to ask
Zhou Yu to surrender.
Yes, Your Highness.
Piggy. Scared you didn't I?
These guys keep tailing me.
How can I have any fun like this?
You're battalion commander.
They have to follow you.
Listen up! Everyone go practice Cuju.
Yes, sir!
It worked!
- Let's have some fun! Great
- Okay.
- What should we play?
- Let's play...
Let's play Ride High.
OK. Come on.
You really are heavy.
Your mother gave you the right nickname.
This isn't high enough. Let's go up there.
Watch your balance.
Be careful.
This high enough for you?
Yeah. Stay still.
- That itches.
- Itches?
Here, let me scratch it.
Much better.
Turn left.
What's so interesting there?
It's just the fleet.
Don't move.
My Lord.
Cao Cao has several
hundred thousand soldiers.
We have only thirty thousand.
We are totally outnumbered.
How can we fight like this?
This will decide the fate
of the Southlands.
We must fight even if we cannot win.
How many arrows do we have?
Not even fifty thousand.
Liu Bei took forty thousand when he fled.
Without those arrows, we cannot fight.
The arrows are my responsibility.
As well they should be.
Your Lord took them.
We need one hundred thousand arrows.
You still think you can handle it?
Fine, if I cannot come up
with one hundred thousand,
...you may take my head.
We only have food for ten days.
I give you ten days' time.
I don't need ten, just three.
We soldiers do not joke.
You said you'd eliminate
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
If not, then what?
You may have my head.
By night, the Milky Way.
By day, snaking clouds.
You were here all night.
What are you up to?
See for yourself.
Wind and water converge here.
The feng shui is excellent.
Glad you're relaxed.
You are worrying me to death.
The twenty ships with crew...
...you requested are ready
There's only one day left.
Where are the arrows?
You haven't made even one.
You should be in a nervous sweat.
My sweat is of no concern.
But see if the tortoise is sweating.
It is.
As I predicted, fog is coming.
What fog?
The only fog here is around my head.
What is this plan of yours?
Nature's secrets cannot be revealed.
Old cow plows the paddy's rows.
Young calf munches on what grows.
You really are something.
Back then you were just
a kid who loved to sing.
Who'd have guessed that kid
would be a Viceroy.
Planting rice is the old man's chore.
We were ten when you clubbed
that bandit from behind.
He spun around and somehow
the club was in my hands.
He gave me the beating of my life.
In the sedan chair the young boy snores.
To this day I still don't understand...
...how that club got into my hand
You're too slow.
You remember that time?
I wrote on the tutor's exam book
in your handwriting...
..."Senile idiot!"
That's right!
He gave me twenty swats across my butt.
Back in those days,
...there was no prank we didn't pull.
I can trick any man I meet.
But with you, I always play the fool.
Bring my sword!
Marvelous!
You are a fine sword dancer.
Are you here as Cao Cao's emissary?
Me?
I can barely speak for myself.
How could I speak for Cao Cao?
I'm not as clever as you...
...but I know what song you're singing.
You do not give me enough credit.
I'd never disrespect a talented
Southerner...
...but to serve Cao Cao is wrong.
You have your Lord and I have mine, but...
No matter.
A few days from now...
...someone will lay Cao Cao's
head at my feet.
You believe me?
Yes, I do.
Your Honor, urgent news!
Can't you see I have a guest?
I know we've no arrows.
If Zhu-ge Liang fails to get more,
...I'll have his head
Maybe our friends
across the river can help.
They have a more important mission.
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun report...
...Cao Cao's head cannot be taken just yet.
I fear...
Do not underestimate them.
Here is their message.
Excellent!
Mr. Jiang.
What are you doing here alone?
Mrs. Zhou? Come sit inside.
Xiao Qiao, bring more wine.
Any more and you'll be drunk.
Come on, we'll drink more upstairs.
Drink more?
Why end a good time?
I heard Cao Cao invaded the Southlands
all for your wife.
Is that so?
Cao Cao has a reputation
for stealing men's wives.
You're drunk More wine.
More? Where?
"We surrendered to Cao Cao...
...not for profit but out of desperation.
We now have the Northerners
entrapped in camp.
Soon we will deliver his decap...
...his decapitated head.
Further reports to come.
Admiral Cai Mao. "
What are you looking at?
Just one of my tricks.
You do love to play tricks on me.
I'll trick you again...
...and again.
Not this time you won't.
Scarecrow, you're more of
a man than that fellow.
That fellow doesn't tell me a thing.
You're a better drinking buddy.
Cheers!
Scarecrow.
Why are we heading for the enemy camp?
You're not surrendering, are you?
The enemy! The enemy is approaching!
Separate ships.
Send the left flank to intercept the enemy!
Faster!
Scarecrow, stop drumming!
What if Cao Cao's men come for us?
They wouldn't dare.
A heavy fog might hide an ambush.
Oh, so you've decided to talk to me.
Ready all archers!
Shoot at first sight!
Ready!
All ships line up!
This is a plot to turn us
against each other.
We're not fools.
Would Zhou Yu use such an obvious trick?
Sometimes the simplest trick...
...is the best way to lead
someone to their death.
Shoot!
Shoot.!
Your Highness,
whether this is a trick or not,
...we should proceed with caution.
What if their navy mutinies?
That would be a disaster.
Shoot!
Besides the letter,
...I heard them mention...
...friends here would get them arrows.
Don't worry.
Scarecrow will protect you.
Cease drumming!
Call Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun
in for questioning.
They are out training the fleet.
If they are not here,
then their handwriting is.
Bring their letter of surrender.
Ready, all ships about-face!
What?
Drum in unison.
Give them a target to shoot.
Aim for the drums.
Shoot!
Drink up.
Watch your seat.
Fire at will!
The handwriting is a perfect match...
...and full of the same mistakes.
This must be the work of Cai Mao.
Shoot!
We return home victorious!
Cheers.
Nothing but scared mice.
Return to your positions!
Thank you Prime Minister for your gift.
Thank you...
Marvelous!
Mr. Zhu-ge! Look...
How did you know the fog was coming?
A clear Milky Way and snaking clouds...
...signal fog is near.
If you know how earth,
sky, yin and yang change,
...then the sun, moon and stars;
...the wind, forest, mountains and fire...
...become soldiers at your command.
So you can read
Mother Nature's moods, huh?
We lost one!
- What a shame...
- Hey, come back!
A small victory hardly
deserves such a reception.
Your Highness.
A small victory?
How many men did the enemy send?
Fog covered the river. Impossible to see.
If you could not see,
how did you repel them?
Firing at will forced retreat.
Firing at will?
How many arrows is that?
About one hundred thousand.
About one hundred thousand!
And why didn't you pursue them?
Fog meant possible ambush, Your Highness.
So...
Again with the fog.
Seems like you are hiding
something in that fog.
Look, a boat is floating this way.
Pull it in...
Your Highness.
Can't you tell a soldier from a scarecrow?
One hundred thousand arrows?
You're mighty generous.
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
I deserve death, Your Highness.
Today it's arrows...
Tomorrow it's my head, am I right?
Zhou Yu is turning us against each other.
No spy is stupid enough to...
Silence!
I trust and honor talented men.
But I abhor deceivers and traitors.
Guards!
Your Highness,
we have trained day and night.
Take them away and behead them.
We swear our loyalty to Your Highness.
Didn't I surrender to a benevolent ruler?
We have trained night and day.
Wait, Your Highness.
If you kill them, who will lead the navy?
Halt!
Ninety-three thousand eight hundred.
Ninety-four thousand.
Ninety-four thousand two hundred.
Ninety-four thousand six hundred.
We'll shoot Cao Cao with his own arrows.
This battle will be interesting.
Concentrate! No mistakes.
Wait.
Don't interrupt!
Two hundred per person.
There'll be no mistakes.
Mr. Zhu-ge, what is this new invention?
A rapid-fire crossbow.
It shoots ten arrows without reloading.
Here, watch.
Great.
Ninety-nine thousand four hundred.
Ninety-nine thousand six hundred.
Impressive!
You know a trifle about weapon design too.
Knowing a trifle about everything
gives life more color.
Your Honor.
Did he reach one hundred thousand?
The total is
ninety-nine thousand six hundred.
Now what?
Well...
Your Honor, it's only four hundred.
Short one is still short.
The law is firm as a mountain.
That's right. So what does the law say?
The law prescribes beheading.
Garbages!
What took you so long?
Hurry and bring them over.
Thank god!
The total is
one hundred thousand two hundred.
Mr. Zhu-ge has completed his mission.
Seems like my head is safe where it is.
How about yours?
You want my head?
Mr. Zhu-ge.
We're just joking.
When I lost, was he joking?
Of course not.
Looks like you haven't lost after all.
Cao Cao has executed
Admirals Cai Mao and Zhang Yun.
I think we've been duped.
Steal the enemy's weapons
then destroy their moral.
Your strategies
worked together brilliantly.
Cao Cao must be going crazy
right about now.
In two or three days,
he will try something desperate.
But this will not be good for Jiang Gan.
I've lost an old friend.
Honored guests...
Zhou Yu is just showing off his cleverness.
He undoubtedly thinks I have gone crazy.
Tell me, do I look crazy?
Not at all...
Come, let us root out the traitor...
...then we can sleep easy. Cheers!
- Jiang Gan.
- Yes
Today you were of great service.
Please drink.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Sir!
Sir! Are you...
Your stupidity was trivial.
But you brought your stupidity upon me.
Hear this!
In two days,
our army shall cross the river...
...and take Red Cliff!
Yes, Your Highness!
All hear this!
In two days the army will cross the river.
What's going on here?
There's a spy! Catch the spy!
Halt!
Don't let him escape!
Grab him!
Piggy, why do they want to hurt you?
It's a misunderstanding
A misunderstanding?
What's going on?
He's a spy.
Nonsense, he is my friend.
Friend? Are you stupid?
Come on, they're beating up the commander.
A fight!
Pit.
Piggy, are you all right?
I have to go.
Piggy!
Where are you going?
My mother is sick. I must go home.
That's very kind of you to visit her.
You should go home too.
No, I'll return after the war.
Fighting means no taxes.
That means more food on the table.
Hurry, go visit your mother.
I will come back to see you.
Ride high.
Don't let him escape!
He's just going to see his mother.
In eighteen years of battle,
...I have never lost
If I fail to capture this tiny cliff,
...I shudder to think
what historians will say.
Yes.
Your Highness.
How are things?
Worse than expected.
The disease's spread has not slowed.
At this rate,
...it will take a month to control.
I respectfully request you
delay the assault.
Stop! Lie still
- Your Highness.
- Sit up.
You are ill and must recuperate.
Man Tun, how can you be ill?
You were always in perfect health.
What is on your mind?
Go ahead.
I want to go home.
I too have not been home for a long time.
I want to see my youngest son.
He is only thirteen.
Younger than you even.
He is kind-hearted and bright.
He has been frail since birth
and is often sick.
Yet in front of me,
...he pretends everything is fine.
Whatever the illness, he endures.
He never complains to me...
...I swore at the start of this war...
...to cleanse the world of warlords.
We must seize Red Cliff
and storm the capital.
Then bring the mud of this land back home...
...and tell our families we were victorious.
We were victorious!
So you all must be strong...
...as must I...
...because I must bring you back home.
Victory...
Greetings everyone.
Sorry for the wait.
We're glad you're back safe.
Did you have any problems?
No. I just fell into the mud.
jumping the stockade.
Shang Xiang.
You're always causing trouble.
Where have you been?
They are ready to attack.
Shang Xiang.
You're back.
Xiao Qiao.
Shang Xiang?
Xiao Qiao...
...please help me pull this.
Go ahead, pull it.
This is a map of Cao Cao's camp.
This tower here...
...is Cao Cao's headquarters.
Their best troops guard it.
The barracks are here.
East and west are well-defended.
The rear hill is weakest.
It's like a tiger that stares ahead...
...but forgets its tail.
The navy is here Put this on.
- You'll catch a chill.
- I'm not cold
A third of their forces...
...are onboard ready for assault.
Warships lead the smaller boats.
Transport ships are in the middle.
This is an interlocked naval formation.
I'm fine.
Every ship is ready for attack or defense.
I was wrong to scold you.
If you were Zhou Yu,
...how would you attack?
He only has enough men for one assault...
...an all-out attack on our fleet.
They will want to attack with fire.
Fire? I doubt it.
Without manpower, they need strength.
Where can they get it? Fire of course.
This is a standard rule of war.
Too bad it won't work.
A northwest wind is blowing.
If they attack our fleet with fire,
...they will be fighting the wind
and burn themselves.
We are the ones who should use fire.
Yes, load the ships with brimstone.
Tomorrow, we shall burn
Red Cliff to the ground!
The map shows.
Cao Cao's army has finished deployment.
Tonight may be the decisive battle.
This is a fight to the death.
Win or lose, we must fight
with everything we have.
Shang Xiang.
What are these lines between the ships?
It sounds funny.
They've locked their boats together...
...to stabilize the fleet...
...so the Northerners won't get seasick.
Enough talk. What is your strategy?
Cao Cao made camp in a bad location.
It is hook-shaped.
This makes return difficult.
If their assault fails,
they cannot fall back.
We should use fire.
The terrain is in our favor.
If we can burn the fleet's vanguard,
...they will be trapped and vulnerable.
Yes, a fire attack!
Just give me ten fire ships.
Two will hit their left and right flanks.
The remaining eight will ram the center.
We'll burn an opening here!
Next, you follow closely and rush in.
No matter how great their numbers,
...we will crush them.
If only we still had Liu Bei's cavalry,
...then we could attack
their camp at the rear.
Then victory would be assured.
This wind is to Cao Cao's advantage.
A northwest wind is blowing.
Sailing into the wind
will burn our own fleet.
Cao Cao knows the wind is on his side.
He will also think of using fire.
Why are you so quiet?
What are you looking at?
Look, those dark clouds in the east...
...are enshrouding the sun
Isn't that rather unusual?
Zhu-ge Liang, what does that mean?
The winds will change.
I know from farming.
If during a warm winter clouds
enshroud the sun,
...then along the Yangtze River...
...an unseasonal wind will blow.
What do you mean unseasonal?
A warm southeast wind.
It blows from southeast to northwest.
What if Cao Cao knows this too?
Only Admiral Cai Mao
would know and he is dead.
Zhu-ge Liang.
Can you predict when it will change?
Tonight or tomorrow morning.
History shows the timing of weather is key.
He who can predict it will win.
We must delay his attack.
Only then will we have a chance at victory.
Greetings, General.
Terrific, just terrific
This fish oil is perfect!
Bigger Yes, General!
No good. Bigger!
Yes, General.
Just how big do you want it?
Go.
That's about right.
Yes! This is it!
See how strong this northwest wind is?
It will never shift.
We'll never get near their navy.
Your Honor, I can fake a defection.
Invent some excuse...
...to punish me with fifty lashes.
I'll fake a surrender in anger.
That way Cao Cao is sure to believe me.
Then I can sail my fire ships in range.
How can you fight after such a beating?
I could never treat a general that way.
Do not lose heart.
The east wind will come.
Your Honor...
Terrible news...
Our Lady has disappeared!
My dear husband,
by the time you read this,
...I will be on the way to Cao Cao's camp.
I will be cautious...
...and only act when the moment is right.
Yet I hope the east wind will come early.
Where there is faith, there is hope.
The clear waters of the Yangtze...
...the emerald leaves of the mountains...
...the birds returning to nest...
...the fisherman singing his evening song.
This is our home,
...our beautiful native land.
Our people gladly give
their lives for her sake.
I cannot stand idly by.
I have been carrying our child
Ping An for three months.
I did not tell you...
...fearing it might distract you.
We cannot in caring for our child...
...and forget the children of
the Southlands.
I want to see them grow up together...
...to have a future where they can play,
...swim, pick flowers...
...and plant rice in peace.
"Your child Ping An "
"Pregnant "
"Do not fear...
...I shall bring Ping An home. "
Some traditions still carry great meaning.
For example, rice flour and sugar...
...stick together like a family at reunion.
Over here! Bring the cart here!
There are sweet rice
dumplings for everyone.
Today is winter solstice,
a time for reunion.
Everyone have some rice dumplings.
Two or three per person! Eat up!
Officers and soldiers alike, come on!
Come on...
Give me a bowl
Zhang Fei, you're making them too big.
Do you want us to choke?
Fine with me. I couldn't be happier.
Zhao Yun.
Has your wound healed
from combat practice?
So long as I can fight,
a wound means nothing.
Guan Yu, how many times
have you read the classics?
If a man of learning does not
understand brotherhood,
...isn't his learning worthless?
My Lord, what are we doing here?
Waiting.
Waiting for what?
Waiting for Zhu-ge Liang.
Waiting for his return, so we can go home.
Do we still have a home?
Sons of the Southlands, listen.
Today is the winter solstice,
...a day for family reunion.
Yet thieves encircle our home.
How can we celebrate like this?
I say let us drive them from this land!
Then we shall have
our celebratory family meal.
Here!
My Lord.
Though I sometimes disagree with you,
...I have never said a word against you.
But this is a choice
between right and wrong.
I acted for the good of us all...
...yet you lecture me for being unrighteous
You have followed me so long and for what?
I just want to ensure we live on.
There are some things I value
more than my life.
Zhou Yu, may your plans come to fruition.
We will fight the good fight.
Zhou Yu's wife is here.
She came alone.
Zhou Yu,
...we must alter our plan of attack
Consider your wife's safety,
...I will send our best men...
...around back to rescue her.
No changes.
All our forces must be
focused on frontal assault.
We cannot divide our strength.
Your Honor, we stand
alone on the battlefield.
Without allied support,
...the chance for victory seems slight.
I have never given up on my dream.
Victory cannot rest on dreams alone.
When will the east wind come?
Based on new observations,
...at around one o'clock.
If at that time you
still trust your friends,
...light a lantern for a signal.
If misfortune befalls Xiao Qiao,
...will you still fight a war of honor?
I saw you once in the back
of your family's estate
Though young, you were
already a great beauty
You were studying the tea ceremony...
...and liked catching butterflies.
Did you launch this war for me?
You believe that?
My father was very fond of you.
At that time, Cao Cao
believed in justice, ideals...
...and loyalty to the Han throne.
He was a young hero.
How else could he have
become Prime Minister?
By killing many people.
I heard many Southland soldiers
have fallen ill.
Yes.
I heard Liu Bei has fled...
...and the alliance is broken.
Yes.
Then Zhou Yu must be a lonely man.
Did he send you?
This was my idea.
Why are you here?
Please withdraw your troops.
Victory is yours.
What need is there to fight on?
No.
Zhou Yu shall kneel before me in surrender.
What is this?
I am not here for my husband...
...but for the people of this kingdom.
Please end this war.
And if I refuse?
Stop playing.
You must witness how I defeat Zhou Yu.
What's on your mind?
Just thinking of a silly friend.
The times make the hero.
After this battle,
...I will have time to savor your tea.
Just one cup?
It'll help you relax.
Fine.
No one's ever given us respect.
So what?
Who cares so long as we respect ourselves?
Listen up!
Our boats will soon charge Cao Cao's fleet.
No man jumps ship until their ships burn.
Yes, sir!
Any problem with that?
No, sir!
That's what I thought.
Have you all written to your families?
Yes.
Don't rush.
Appreciate the tea's color and bouquet.
Oh.
Why is the Prime Minister
waiting to attack?
The wind is behaving strangely.
I know.
He is drinking tea with that woman.
Tea?
What makes brewing tea so difficult?
Leaves, heat, water, and utensils...
...all demand study.
Yet the hardest is boiling water.
Boiling water?
Look!
The wind has stopped.
At first boil, bubbles hiss
and resemble tiny fish eyes.
At second boil,
the edge simmers like a fountain.
This is when tea is finest.
At third boil,
the water seethes and spurts.
Any further and the water
is past its prime.
Your Honor, the wind seems about to shift.
It's time to attack
What are we waiting for?
Our allies.
What allies?
Liu Bei fled days ago.
This is all part of Zhou Yu's plan.
Some plans are best kept quiet.
Enough! It is full!
Your Highness...
...don't you see your true self
reflected in this tea?
Your heart is overflowing with ambition.
It's too full to let other people in.
You've carried this
full heart to Red Cliff.
Someone here shall pour
that heart onto the floor.
Your Highness.
You do not understand the art of tea.
Your Honor, tell us what we must do.
At two o'clock,
...the ten fire ships
will ram Cao Cao's fleet...
...burning through their vanguard.
With the fleet broken,
...Zhao Yun will hit the east gate...
...to divert their attention.
Liu Bei, Guan Yu, and Zhang Fei...
...will overwhelm Cao Cao's camp
from the west gate.
Doctor!
Your Highness!
Call Doctor Hua Tuo. My head aches.
Your Highness, Hua Tuo has left.
- What did you say?
- Hua Tuo is gone.
Cast off!
What is this wind?
It's an easterly wind, Your Highness.
It shifted? Impossible!
Enemy ships approaching!
General, enemy ships approaching!
Hurry, separate the ships!
Separate ships!
What is that?
That is their lanterns, Your Highness.
Forward.
- Zhou Yu.
- I have done all I can.
Tonight will decide the fate of the empire.
There must be no mistakes.
Zhu-ge Liang,
...you weren't lying after all!
Report!
Boats are approaching fast.
Separate ships immediately.
Separation has already begun.
Light the fires!
Forward.
Hurry over here!
All speed ahead!
Hurry, separate the ships.
Faster.
Retreat! Protect the main gate!
Faster, toward Cao Cao's flagship!
Strike as powerful as thunder.
Charge!
Go ahead. Charge!
Follow me.
Shoot!
Launch catapults!
Hurry, the enemy is approaching
Look, over there.
Your Highness! Terrible news!
They have broken through the stockade!
Why are you panicking?
Do not forget you are a general.
I...
Try to endure the pain!
Reinforce Zhang Fei! Move!
Your Highness, the rear gate
is under surprise attack.
It is Liu Bei's allied forces.
Liu Bei?
Free the horses!
Pull!
Shoot!
General Gan,
...we must save energy for inside.
You must break down this gate...
...so we can join our allies...
...otherwise all is lost.
- No problem.
- Good luck
Halt!
Tear down the barricade!
Shoot!
Forward.
Attack the main gate.
Come on soldier!
Hang in there.
General Gan!
Individual bombs aren't strong enough.
Run! The fire is coming!
Give me all your fire bombs.
There's only three left.
No retreat! No surrender!
This is it!
All forces attack!
Shoot!
Your Highness.
The navy is lost.
East, south, and west...
all three sides have been sunk.
It seems like they went up in flames too.
Yes, Your Highness.
All is quiet below.
The fire is too fierce!
Stay together at all costs!
Don't get separated!
Your Highness.
Perhaps retreat is best.
Retreat?
With our best soldiers still remaining?
They would give their lives for me.
Even if all would die, they must fight.
This is military power.
All together! Charge!
Fight me if you dare.
Come back here!
Come on, you traitor!
General!
Don't give up, my brother.
Guan Yu! Where is Liu Bei?
All speed ahead!
Break formation!
Launch spears!
Forward!
Crush them or die trying!
Hang in there.
I oversaw the end of every warlord.
I saw the end of one here and one there.
The end of all but here...
Just in time.
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
I said we would meet again.
Gan Xing sacrificed himself.
But not in vain.
The fire is approaching!
We must save Xiao Qiao now!
First find Cao Cao.
We have lost...
...all because of that accursed woman.
She ruined our chance to attack.
I'll kill her.
Kill her.
Come no further.
Don't let the enemy through.
That way, quickly...
Protect the Prime Minister! Get them!
Pit?
Pit!
It's me, Piggy.
Piggy?
Piggy.
You came to see me.
I said I would.
Piggy...
Still want to play Ride High?
I'll kill that witch.
Don't move!
Zhou Yu.
Viceroy Zhou.
The traitor Cao Cao Silence!
You shall call me Prime Minister.
I never guessed I'd lose to a gust of wind.
Because you don't understand
the Will of Heaven.
I never dreamed I'd be
defeated by a cup of tea.
For you, war was just a tea ceremony.
Such a pity!
You never knew what you were fighting for!
I come by order of the Emperor...
...to subdue rebels like you.
We are not rebelling against the Emperor...
- ... but against you.
- You pest!
Little boy...
This has been quite an enjoyable hunt.
What do you want to hunt?
Tiger.
By the looks of you.
You are a far cry from your father.
Shoot!
I am prime Minister of the Emperor's court.
Death is too good for rebels like you.
If you declare allegiance to me,
...I can pardon you.
Kneel down, all of you.
Your time is over.
Lay down your sword.
Your Highness, kill them!
Kill them all.
Xiao Qiao!
Are you both safe?
We are both fine.
We lost!
All because of you!
Kneel down before me.
Kneel to me and I will spare Xiao Qiao.
We won't let you harm her.
"We"?
You mean"them"?
That motley troop?
They are my friends.
War knows no friends.
Tomorrow, they shall be your enemies.
General!
Push her off! Die!
Your Honor!
Are you both all right?
Let's go.
I promise I will take you home.
Go.
Go back to where you came from.
There is no victor here.
Meng Meng.
Go on now, go.
From division comes unity,
and from unity, division...
...Liu Bei won't stand being second best.
One day, we will face
each other on the battlefield.
No man can tell the future.
The world is full of heroes.
But you're the one I most fear offending.
You would be an opponent I truly fear.
Me?
I'd best return home and get some sleep.
Are you a good farmer?
I planted lotus flowers once...
...but none lived long.
Do not be humble
You have brought peace to the land.
In this alliance, I found true friends.
No matter what may happen,
...this experience is engraved in my heart.
I too will not forget.
Zhu-ge Liang,
...when Meng Meng has grown,
do not make her a war horse.
Don't worry.
These hands helped birth her.
I shall always cherish her.